<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R | Final Project - Police Shootings in the US</title>
    <link>/category/r/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/category/r/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing from Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>/post/fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This analysis is going to explore some of the different circumstances behind fatal police shootings in where the victim was fleeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;type-of-fleeing&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Type of Fleeing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 below shows the proportion of those who do not flee, who do, and if they are fleeing, what method of fleeing that these individuals are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1.
&lt;em&gt;The proportion of fatal police shootings by flee method over time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 depicts the proportion of fleeing by car decreasing and every other method is seen increasing, in recent. The proportion of the incidents where fleeing method is not recorded is increasing every year, almost to the same degree that the “Not Fleeing” method is decreasing, this should be taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;unarmed&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Unarmed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 2. &lt;em&gt;Accounts for the proportion of method of fleeing of unarmed victims of fatal police shootings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless src=&#34;../unarmed.html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1.
&lt;em&gt;A table of the proportion of unarmed victims by fleeing method&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question proposed is if the proportion of flee method by individuals unarmed reflected Figure 1. Figure 2 is that visualization. Of those indiduals who were ivolved with fatal police shootings, most are not fleeing much like overall fatal police shootings. We also see that a larger proportion of unarmed individuals are fleeing by foot than the overall population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;influential-findings-and-comments&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Influential Findings and Comments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the victims of fatal police shootings are not fleeing from the police officers. It is the same for those individuals who are unarmed, though for those who are unarmed, a larger proportion is fleeing by &lt;code&gt;Car&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Foot&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I think is very interesting to note is why is the proportion of those &lt;code&gt;flee&lt;/code&gt; levels &lt;code&gt;Not Recorded&lt;/code&gt; is increasing. Over time we’re seeing less people not fleeing from the police and every other method is increasing to even a small degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat and Race</title>
      <link>/post/threat-and-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/threat-and-race/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;introduction&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has always been a debate between the links of fatal police shootings and the victims. There has even been insinuations that race has an effect on the threatening nature of these individuals. That interactions with police among specific racial groups might, on average be more aggressive or carry higher risk. This topic often sparks outrage within the black and POC communities and within law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to to explore this sensitive topic and try to make some inferential findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-data&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Data&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-police-shootings&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have three variables to look at: &lt;code&gt;attack&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;other&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;undetermined&lt;/code&gt;. Attack constitutes as the individual was reported to have posed immediate threat to the officer. &lt;code&gt;Other&lt;/code&gt; is every other level of threat and &lt;code&gt;undetermined&lt;/code&gt; is for any circumstance that through the vetting process, threat level could not be determined.
Keep in mind how the level of threat is determined, as explained in the home page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the visualization of the raw numbers/counts. Figure 1 below shows the level of reported threat by race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-threat-and-race.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1.
&lt;em&gt;Amount of Fatal Police Shootings by Race since 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three graphs look identical. The only visual difference is the volume of the counts. I think in this case, looking at the proportions will be more inferential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;when-victims-are-threatening&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;When Victims are Threatening&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to explore some general statistics of when a victim pose an immediate threat to a police officer’s life. Figure 2 depics a boxplot with the proportions of those who pose immediate threat to an officers life by race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-threat-and-race.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 2.
&lt;em&gt;Box plot and distribution of the proportions of victims who are recorded to have posed a threat to an officer’s life by race from 2015 to current.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2015 to current, it is depicted through Figure 2 that the largest proportion of those who are recorded to be threatening have tended to be White, then Black, Hispanic, Not Recorded, Asian, Native and Other, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = race.proportion ~ race, data = .)
## 
## Residuals:
##       Min        1Q    Median        3Q       Max 
## -0.094020 -0.004781 -0.000993  0.011865  0.185885 
## 
## Coefficients:
##               Estimate Std. Error t value Pr(&amp;gt;|t|)    
## (Intercept)   0.013992   0.019169   0.730 0.470298    
## raceBlack     0.227372   0.027109   8.387 6.83e-10 ***
## raceHispanic  0.132954   0.027109   4.904 2.14e-05 ***
## raceNative   -0.001808   0.027109  -0.067 0.947208    
## raceNR        0.106430   0.027109   3.926 0.000387 ***
## raceOther    -0.005531   0.027109  -0.204 0.839508    
## raceWhite     0.442641   0.027109  16.328  &amp;lt; 2e-16 ***
## ---
## Signif. codes:  0 &amp;#39;***&amp;#39; 0.001 &amp;#39;**&amp;#39; 0.01 &amp;#39;*&amp;#39; 0.05 &amp;#39;.&amp;#39; 0.1 &amp;#39; &amp;#39; 1
## 
## Residual standard error: 0.04695 on 35 degrees of freedom
## Multiple R-squared:  0.9258, Adjusted R-squared:  0.9131 
## F-statistic: 72.76 on 6 and 35 DF,  p-value: &amp;lt; 2.2e-16&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display 1. &lt;em&gt;Simple linear regression model where &lt;code&gt;race&lt;/code&gt; predicts the proportion of &lt;code&gt;threat_level&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##             Df Sum Sq Mean Sq F value Pr(&amp;gt;F)    
## race         6 0.9625  0.1604   72.76 &amp;lt;2e-16 ***
## Residuals   35 0.0772  0.0022                   
## ---
## Signif. codes:  0 &amp;#39;***&amp;#39; 0.001 &amp;#39;**&amp;#39; 0.01 &amp;#39;*&amp;#39; 0.05 &amp;#39;.&amp;#39; 0.1 &amp;#39; &amp;#39; 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display 2. &lt;em&gt;One-way ANOVA on proportion means by race&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-threat-and-race.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-5-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 3. &lt;em&gt;Confidence intervals of the differencein mean levels of race. Via Tukey’s comparison of means.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##   Tukey multiple comparisons of means
##     95% family-wise confidence level
##     factor levels have been ordered
## 
## Fit: aov(formula = model)
## 
## $race
##                        diff          lwr        upr     p adj
## Native-Other    0.003723252 -0.081017747 0.08846425 0.9999993
## Asian-Other     0.005531169 -0.079209831 0.09027217 0.9999930
## NR-Other        0.111960716  0.027219716 0.19670172 0.0036763
## Hispanic-Other  0.138485474  0.053744474 0.22322647 0.0002168
## Black-Other     0.232902840  0.148161841 0.31764384 0.0000000
## White-Other     0.448172295  0.363431295 0.53291329 0.0000000
## Asian-Native    0.001807917 -0.082933083 0.08654892 1.0000000
## NR-Native       0.108237464  0.023496464 0.19297846 0.0053777
## Hispanic-Native 0.134762222  0.050021222 0.21950322 0.0003255
## Black-Native    0.229179588  0.144438588 0.31392059 0.0000000
## White-Native    0.444449043  0.359708043 0.52919004 0.0000000
## NR-Asian        0.106429547  0.021688547 0.19117055 0.0064548
## Hispanic-Asian  0.132954305  0.048213305 0.21769530 0.0003962
## Black-Asian     0.227371671  0.142630672 0.31211267 0.0000000
## White-Asian     0.442641126  0.357900126 0.52738213 0.0000000
## Hispanic-NR     0.026524758 -0.058216242 0.11126576 0.9554078
## Black-NR        0.120942124  0.036201125 0.20568312 0.0014385
## White-NR        0.336211579  0.251470579 0.42095258 0.0000000
## Black-Hispanic  0.094417366  0.009676367 0.17915837 0.0208135
## White-Hispanic  0.309686821  0.224945821 0.39442782 0.0000000
## White-Black     0.215269454  0.130528455 0.30001045 0.0000000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display 3. &lt;em&gt;Table from the visualization Figure 3. provides.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Warning in boxplot.default(split(mf[[response]], mf[-response], drop = drop, :
## NAs introduced by coercion
## Warning in text.default(c(1:nlevels(r.proportion$race)),
## a$stats[nrow(a$stats), : NAs introduced by coercion&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-threat-and-race.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 4. &lt;em&gt;Connecting letters boxplot. Different letters result in significant differences between means&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Display 1 is the output of a regression model in where we predict the proportion of the &lt;code&gt;attack&lt;/code&gt; threat level via race. Our R-squared adjusted=.9131 and the p-value=2.2e-16 meaning that the regression is an appropriate model to predict the proportion of individuals that pose a threat on an officer’s life by race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regression model:
&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[ predicted(proportion) = 0.014 + 0.227(Black) + 0.1323(Hispanic) -0.002(Native) + 0.106(Not Recorded) - 0.006(Other) + 0.443(White) \]&lt;/span&gt;
91.31% of the variation in proportion of those who are threatening is explained through the differences in race, but are these differences significant?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A One-way ANOVA (Display 2) was done to test if there is at least one mean proportion from a single race is significantly different to another. The p-value&amp;lt;2e-16. We have enough statistical evidence to conclude at least one mean proportion of one race was significantly different than another race. A Tukey’s comparison post hoc to see what these differences are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 and Display 3 shows the output for the Tukey’s comparison of means. The output here can be hard to interpret, so a connecting letters plot was made in Figure 4. Significant differences are denoted as having different letters above each boxplot. &lt;code&gt;Asian&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Native&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Other&lt;/code&gt; all have the same letter, so their mean proportions are not significantly different from one another, though they are significantly different than the rest of the races. &lt;code&gt;Hispanic&lt;/code&gt; and the proportions of those who race is recorded as &lt;code&gt;Not Recorded&lt;/code&gt; have no significant differences to each other. &lt;code&gt;Black&lt;/code&gt; is significantly different than all other races. &lt;code&gt;White&lt;/code&gt; is also significanly different than all other races. “a” is the smallest mean proportion while “d” is the largest mean proportion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;inferential-findings-and-conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Inferential Findings and Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;is-there-a-correlation-between-threat-level-and-race&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Is there a correlation between threat level and race?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing a simple regression analysis, we find that a linear model in where race predicts the proportion of individuals that posed a threat to an officer life, is appropriate. We do not have significant evidence to say that there isn’t a correlation, in fact we have strong statistical evidence that we do. Our model also accounts for 91.31% in the variation of predicted proportion just from race alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-are-these-differences&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What are these differences?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like how it is described in the One-way ANOVA and Tukey’s post hoc, &lt;code&gt;Asian&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Native&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Other&lt;/code&gt; all have predicted proportions that show no significant difference, as they are in group, “a”. &lt;code&gt;Hispanic&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Not Recorded&lt;/code&gt; also show no significant difference, group, “b”. &lt;code&gt;Black&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;White&lt;/code&gt; are also in their own category, “c” and “d”, respectfully. This means that &lt;code&gt;White&lt;/code&gt; has the largest mean proportion, followed by &lt;code&gt;Black&lt;/code&gt;, then the group containing &lt;code&gt;Hispanic&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Not Recorded&lt;/code&gt;, followed by the group containing &lt;code&gt;Asian&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Native&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Other&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusions&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From our findings above, we have evidence to say that the mean proportion of &lt;code&gt;White&lt;/code&gt; people make up the largest proportion of those who posed an immediate threat to an officer’s life in a fatal police shooting. &lt;code&gt;Asian&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Native&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Other&lt;/code&gt; make up the smallest proportion. While we do have a correlation and a good regression model to predict the proportion based on race, I do not think it is appropriate to say that race will predict an individual’s threat level. In this case correlation does not mean causation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can find the proportion of those who pose a threat to a police officer is more likely to be White than any other race from the fact that 70% or so of the US population is White. White people also make up 40% of all the fatal police shootings It makes sense to have a higher proportion in that sense. We also have other variables to think of. Threat level is mainly based on perception and what is reported. Police can perceive an individual’s threat level based on bias and make a report that the individual did pose immediate threat to the officer’s life. Also, the data set includes social media and other means to record an individual’s theat level. So to make inferences beyond the scope of what statistical tests done is not appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Mental Illness and Fatal Police Shootings</title>
      <link>/post/exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;mental-illness&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mental Illness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a statistic that people mental illness are 15 times more likely to be shot in a police encounter than the lay person. We can think about people like Shukri Ali Said who’s sister called 911 for aid when Said had a mental break. Police had found Said at an intersection with a knife and shot her 5 times, resulting in her death. We can think about Saheed Vassell. A man with a recorded mental illness, who also had a fatal police shooting. Vassell pointed a pipe at a police officer and was shot. We can think about the many people with mental and intellectual illnesses who had fatal police encounters and think about the possible different roots of the problem; the history of social stigma of treatment, to the processes of deinstitutionalization, to the defunding of existing community services like education, affordable housing, social and health services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to explore the effects of mental illness and fatal police encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;general-statistics&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;General Statistics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the dataset &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-police-shootings&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless src=&#34;../d1.html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1
&lt;em&gt;General descriptive statistics of fatal police shootings overall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1
&lt;em&gt;Boxplot of the mean fatal police encounters by race over the years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless src=&#34;../d2.html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 2
&lt;em&gt;Mean of police shooting by race aggregated by year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the two tables shown above, we get a good picture fatal police shootings by signs of mental illness, from the years 2015 to current day. White people make up more than 70% of the US population, so it makes sense that white people will make up the most of police shootings in just raw numbers. Look at Figure 1 for the example. If we do some data crunching, we wil see something interesting. Since 2015, even though white people make up more than 70% of the population, 45% of fatal shootings involve white victims, which is disproportionate. If we factor in mental illness, overall, almost 30% of the White victims of fatal police shootings showed signs of mental illness. Of Black victims: 14.3%, of Asian: 24.7%, of Hispanic: 17.2%, of Native American: 17.9%. Overall, 28.9% of fatal police shooting victims are recorded as showing signs of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;de-escalation&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;De-escalation?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If more than 1 in 4 victims of fatal police shootings involve mental illness, were there attempts to subdue these victims besides shooting? The dataset I’m working with involve whether a taser was used to de-escalate along with shooting via the variable &lt;code&gt;manner_of_death&lt;/code&gt;. There were only two categories, &lt;code&gt;shot&lt;/code&gt;, and, &lt;code&gt;shot and Tasered&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Figure 2, we see that with the fatal police shootings involving victims that showed signs of mental illness, less than 10% in every year have on record that the police tried to deploy a taser as a means of subduing the victim. we actually see a dip in 2018 and is slowly starting to rise again. We are only through a little more than half of the year, but this dataset is updated real time, so this graph will always be current.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-9-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 3
&lt;em&gt;Taser deployed with victims showing signs of mental illness by race&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 offers more insight. Overall, through all years, White victims that involve deployment of a taser: 47.8%, Native American: 1.11%, Hispanic: 17.8%, Black: 23.3%, Asian: 3.3%. We also see that the proportion of the use and deployment of a taser is more steadily increasing among black and white victims, those who make up the majority of victims of fatal police shootings. The percentage of hispanic victims look to be increasing to a small degree, but it may be attributed to the decrease in proportion of victims with race not being recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With almost 28.9% of all fatal police shootings involve the victims showing signs of mental illness. Of those instances, less than 10% every year are recorded that other means than just shooting a gun were used to subdue the victim. Figure 3 shows the ratio of those instances by race with white and black percentages increasing since 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It still begs the question. If 28.9% of victims of fatal police shootings show signs of mental illness, why do 10% of those cases have other means besides shooting as a way to subdue these individuals? I do think it is important to note that certain states have banned the use of tasers. However, could these instances of mental breaks or threatening individuals with mental illnesses been avoided all together? Should we have invested more in social services and health services? These are questions that can’t be answered with this dataset alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
