<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R | Final Project - Police Shootings in the US</title>
    <link>/category/r/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>R</title>
      <link>/category/r/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking at Fatal Police Shootings and Victims Fleeing</title>
      <link>/post/fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;fleeing-and-some-implications&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Fleeing and Some Implications&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Stockton, Ca it’s never really surprising to hear about a police chase in where the suspect gets shot and then passes away. It’s not surprising when we hear of people fleeing from the police when the situation escalates. What is surprising to hear is when a law enforcement officer is prosecuted for the death of a fleeing sispect. In Georgia, a police officer had a fatal encounter with &lt;a href=&#34;https://apnews.com/ae503a6672a34aff873260456224652f/Manslaughter-charge:-Georgia-officer-shot-fleeing-black-man&#34;&gt;a man who was fleeing&lt;/a&gt; was charged with manslaughter. A police officer was charged for shooting and death of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://apnews.com/f721e40873ef4b06ac2c5e6c0200d0f8/Officer-charged-in-death-of-black-teen-who-was-shot-in-back&#34;&gt;teenager who fleed after a traffic stop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis is going to explore some of the different circumstances behind fatal police shootings in where the victim was fleeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;type-of-fleeing&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Type of Fleeing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 1 below shows the proportion of those who do not flee, who do, and if they are fleeing, what method of fleeing are these individuals using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#proportion are killed while attempting to flee
shootings %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(count = 1) %&amp;gt;%
  aggregate(count ~ flee + year, data = ., sum) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(year) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(proportion = count / sum(count)) %&amp;gt;%
  ggplot() +
    geom_line(mapping = aes(x = year, y = proportion, color = flee)) +
    ggtitle(&amp;quot;Proportion of Fatal Police Shooting by Flee Method&amp;quot;) + 
    xlab(&amp;quot;Year&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Proportion&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-28-fatal-police-shooting-and-fleeing.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1
&lt;em&gt;The proportion of fatal police shootings by flee method over time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration of Mental Illness and Fatal Police Shootings</title>
      <link>/post/exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;mental-illness&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mental Illness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistic that many post on their social media stories cites that people with mental illness are 15 times more likely to be shot in a police encounter than the lay person. We can think about people like Shukri Ali Said who’s sister called 911 for aid when Said had a mental break. Police had found Said at an intersection with a knife and shot her 5 times, resulting in her death. We can think about Saheed Vassell. A man with a recorded mental illness, who also had a fatal police shooting. Vassell pointed a pipe at a police officer and was shot. We can think about the many people with mental and intellectual illnesses who had fatal police encounters and think about the possible different roots of the problem; the history of social stigma of treatment, to the processes of deinstitutionalization, to the defunding of existing community services like education, affordable housing, social and health services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to explore the effects of mental illness and fatal police encounters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;general-statistics&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;General Statistics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the dataset &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-police-shootings&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mental.illness &amp;lt;- shootings %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(count = 1) %&amp;gt;%
  aggregate(count ~  race + signs_of_mental_illness + year, data = ., sum) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(race, signs_of_mental_illness) %&amp;gt;%
  summarise(mean = mean(count),
            sd = sd(count),
            min = min(count),
            max = max(count)) 
## `summarise()` regrouping output by &amp;#39;race&amp;#39; (override with `.groups` argument)
d1 &amp;lt;- mental.illness %&amp;gt;%
  datatable()


  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless src=&#34;../d1.html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1
&lt;em&gt;General descriptive statistics of fatal police shootings overall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ag.year &amp;lt;- shootings %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(count = 1) %&amp;gt;%
  aggregate(count ~  race + signs_of_mental_illness + year, data = ., sum) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(race, signs_of_mental_illness, year) %&amp;gt;%
  summarise(mean = mean(count))
## `summarise()` regrouping output by &amp;#39;race&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;signs_of_mental_illness&amp;#39; (override with `.groups` argument)
  
d2 &amp;lt;- ag.year %&amp;gt;%
  datatable()


ag.year %&amp;gt;%
  ggplot() +
  geom_point(mapping = aes(x = race, y = mean), color = &amp;quot;gray&amp;quot;) +
  geom_boxplot(mapping = aes(x = race, y = mean, fill = signs_of_mental_illness)) +
  theme_bw() + ggtitle(&amp;quot;Average Shootings by Mental Illness&amp;quot;) + xlab(&amp;quot;Race&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Average&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 1
&lt;em&gt;Boxplot of the mean fatal police encounters by race over the years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe seamless src=&#34;../d2.html&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;500&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 2
&lt;em&gt;Mean of police shooting by race aggregated by year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the two tables shown above, we get a good picture of the general look of fatal police encounters by signs of mental illness, from the years 2015 to current day. White people make up more than 70% of the US population, so it makes sense that white people will make up the most of police shootings in just raw numbers. Look at Figure 1 for the example. If we do some data crunching, we wil see something interesting. Since 2015, even though white people make up more than 70% of the population, 45% of fatal shootings involve white victims, which is disproportionate. If we factor in mental illness, overall, almost 30% of the white victims of fatal police shootings showed signs of mental illness. Of black victims: 14.3%, of asian: 24.7%, of hispanic: 17.2%, of native american: 17.9%. Overall, 28.9% of fatal police shooting victims are recorded as showing signs of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;were-there-attempts-of-de-escalation&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Were there attempts of de-escalation?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If more than 1 in 4 victims of fatal police shootings involve mental illness, were there attempts to subdue these victims besides shooting? The dataset I’m working with involve whether a taser was used to de-escalate along with shooting via the variable ‘manner_of_death’. There were only two categories, “shot”, and, “shot and Tasered”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;shootings %&amp;gt;%
  filter(signs_of_mental_illness == &amp;quot;True&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(count = 1) %&amp;gt;%
  aggregate(count ~ manner_of_death + year, data = ., sum) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(year) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(prop = count / sum(count)) %&amp;gt;%
  ggplot() +
  geom_line(mapping = aes(x = year, y = prop, color = manner_of_death)) +
  theme_bw() + xlab(&amp;quot;Year&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Proportion&amp;quot;) + ggtitle(&amp;quot;Victims with Mental Illness&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-7-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In figure 2, we see that with the fatal police shootings involving victims that showed signs of mental illness, less than 10% in every year have on record that the police tried to deploy a taser as a means of subduing the victim. we actually see a dip in 2018 and is slowly starting to rise again. We are only through a little more than half of the year, but this dataset is updated real time, so this graph will always be current.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;shootings %&amp;gt;%
  filter(signs_of_mental_illness == &amp;quot;True&amp;quot;, manner_of_death == &amp;quot;shot and Tasered&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(count = 1) %&amp;gt;%
  aggregate(count ~ manner_of_death + year + race, data = ., sum) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(year) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(prop = count / sum(count)) %&amp;gt;%
  ggplot() +
  geom_smooth(mapping = aes(x = year, y = prop, color = race)) +
  theme_bw() + xlab(&amp;quot;Year&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Proportion&amp;quot;) + ggtitle(&amp;quot;Victims with Mental Illness by Race&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-08-26-exploration-of-mental-illness-and-fatal-police-shootings.en_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-9-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
Figure 3
&lt;em&gt;Taser deployed with victims showing signs of mental illness by race&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 3 offers more insight. Overall, through all years, white victims that involve deployment of a taser: 47.8%, native american: 1.11%, hispanic: 17.8%, black: 23.3%, asian: 3.3%. We also see that the proportion of the use and deployment of a taser is more steadily increasing among black and white victims, those who make up the majority of victims of fatal police shootings. The percentage of hispanic victims look to be increasing to a small degree, but it may be attributed to the decrease in proportion of victims with race not being recorded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With almost 28.9% of all fatal police shootings involve the victims showing signs of mental illness. Of those instances, less than 10% every year are recorded that other means than just shooting a gun were used to subdue the victim. Figure 3 shows the ratio of those instances by race with white and black percentages increasing since 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It still begs the question. If 28.9% of victims of fatal police shootings show signs of mental illness, why do 10% of those cases have other means besides shooting as a way to subdue these individuals? I do think it is important to note that certain states have banned the use of tasers. However, could these instances of mental breaks or threatening individuals with mental illnesses been avoided all together? Should we have invested more in social services and health services? These are questions that can’t be answered with this dataset alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
